RG 074:036, Lucius B. Barbour Genealogical Collection
Connecticut State Library
- Collection, circa 1900-1930
  - Notes from probate records, Hartford District. 1635-1750, 1 volume (Box 10, Volume 81)
  - Abstract of probate records, Pomfret District. 1752-1906, 2 volumes (Box 10, Volume 82)
    Arranged alphabetically. Part 1: A-H; Part2: I-Z.
  - Genealogical notes compiled from probate records, Suffield and Windsor, Conn. after 1800. circa 1830, 1 volume (Box 9, Volume 83)
  - Genealogical notes compiled from probate records from Wethersfield, Conn. after 1800. circa 1830, 1 volume (Box 10, Volume 84)
  - Genealogical notes compiled from probate records, Windham District. 1719-1737, 1 volume (Box 10, Volume 85)
  - Abstracts of probate records, Pomfret and Woodstock Districts. 1752-1902, 3 volumes (Box 11, Volume 86)
    Arranged alphabetically. Part 1: A-F; Part 2: G-N; Part 3: N-Z.
  - Barber family genealogical notes. 1613-1804, 1 volume (Box 11, Volume 87)
  - Barber ancestry and descendants of John Barbour of Canton, Conn. and Sheldon, N.Y. 1613-1789, 1 volume, typescript (Box 11, Volume 88)
  - Brewster book, 1593-1830, 1 volume (Box 11, Volume 89)
  - Genealogical notes on the Burt, Colton and Cooley families. 1672-1847, 1 volume (Box 11, Volume 90)
  - Genealogical notes on the Case family. 1658-1861, 1 volume (Box 11, Volume 91)
  - Genealogical notes on the Day family. 1604-1819, 1 volume (Box 12, Volume 92)
  - Records of the descendants of Thomas Clarke, Plymouth, 1623-1697 / compiled by Rev. William W. Johnson, 1 volume (Box 12, Volume 93)
    A copy is available at
  - Genealogical notes on the Hart family. 1704-1730, 1 volume (Box 12, Volume 94)
  - Genealogical notes on the Dart and Shaler families. 1664-1824, 1 volume (Box 12, Volume 95)
  - Genealogical notes on the Fitch family. 1634-1882, 1 volume (Box 12, Volume 96)
  - The Fitch family. 1596-1881, 1 volume, typescript (Box 12, Volume 97)
  - The descendants in eastern Connecticut of Sergeant Thomas Howlett of Boston and Ipswich, Mass. 1630-1884, 1 volume, typescript (Box 12, Volume 98)
  - An account of the Jaudon family / by Edwin Jaquett Sellers, 1 volume, typescript; A copy is available at (Box 12, Volume 99)
  - Marsh genealogy. 1618-1850, 1 volume (Box 12, Volume 100)
  - The descendants of John Scarborough of Roxbury. 1646-1799, 2 volumes (Box 12, Volume 101)
  - Genealogical notes on the family of Rev. Henry Smith of Wethersfield., 1 volume (Box 13, Volume 102)
  - Genealogical notes on the Stebbins family. 1670-1850, 1 volume (Box 13, Volume 103)
  - Index to volumes 1-2 of the genealogical records of the Connecticut Society of Colonial Wars., 1 volume (Box 13, Volume 104)
  - Genealogical notes from Connecticut family Bible records. 1742-1872., 1 volume (Box 12, Volume 105)
  - Genealogical notes on early Connecticut settlers. 1635-, 1 volume (Box 12, Volume 106)
  - Genealogical notes on Connecticut families. 1640-1850, 1 volume (Box 13, Volume 107)
  - Birth and marriage records of some Connecticut people. 1748-1800, 1 volume (Box 13, Volume 108)
  - Early families of East Haddam. 1662-1804, 1 volume (Box 13, Volume 109)
  - Family Genealogical data. 1645-1846, 10 volumes (Box 13)
    - Part 1 (Box 13, Folder 110)
      Family names: Adkins; Alsop; Andrews; Bagg; Baldwin; Barbour; Barnard; Barnes; Birchard; Bird.
    - Part 2 (Box 13, Folder 110)
      Family names: Bliss; Bronson; Buell; Burr; Burt; Buttolph; Button; Case.
    - Part 3 (Box 13, Folder 110)
      Family names: Calkins; Clark; Day; Dickinson; Douglass; Edgerton; Foote; Gridley; Hillard; Howlett; Hough; Lord; Rogers; Royce; Spencer; Stanton.
    - Part 4 (Box 13, Folder 110)
      Family names: Chapin; Clarke; Coley; Coulton; Cooley; Cooper; Cowles; Day.
    - Part 5 (Box 13, Folder 110)
      Family names: Dorchester; Drake; Dumbleton; Eggleston; Ely; Eno; Gardner; Gilbert; Grant; Griswold; Hall; Hazard; Higley; Hill.
    - Part 6 (Box 14, Folder 110)
      Family names: Hinsdale; Hitchcock; Holcomb; Holton; Hopkins; Howard; Humphrey; Kellogg; King; Kitcherrell; Lamb; Leonard; Loomis.
    - Part 7 (Box 14, Folder 110)
      Family names: Lord; Marsh; Merrick; Merrill; Mills; Moore; Morgan; Morris; Mygatt; Onre; Palmer; Pendleton; Pettibone; Phelps; Preston; Prudden.
    - Part 8 (Box 14, Folder 110)
      Family names: Rosewell; Rowe; Rutherford; Scott; Sedgwick; Shephard; Skinner; Spencer; Stanley; Stebbins; Steel; Stone; Talcott; Thomas; Treat; Trowbridge; Wadsworth; Walker.
    - Part 9 (Box 14, Folder 110)
      Family names: Warriner; Watson; Webstrer; Wheadon; Wheeler; White; Whiting; Wilcox; Williams; Wolcott; Woodward; Wright.
    - Part 10 (Box 14, Folder 110)
      Family genealogical data.
      Arranged alphabetically. Index of names at front of volume.
  - Genealogical notes on Hartford families, 2 volumes (Box 15, Volume 111)
    Arranged alphabetically. Part 1: A-Mi; Part Mo-W.
  - Abstract of genealogical records of New Haven, Conn. 1650-1850, 6 volumes (Box 15)
    - Part 1: A-B (Box 15, Volume 112)
    - Part 2: C-G (Box 15, Volume 112)
    - Part 3: H-Mo (Box 16, Volume 112)
    - Part 4: Mo-R (Box 16, Volume 112)
    - Part 5: S-T (Box 16, Volume 112)
    - Part 6: U-Y (Box 16, Volume 112)
  - Abstract of genealogical records of Norwich, Conn. 1700-1852, 6 volumes
    - Part 1: A-B (Box 17, Volume 113)
    - Part 2: C-F (Box 17, Volume 113)
    - Part 3: G-H (Box 18, Volume 113)
    - Part 4: I-M (Box 18, Volume 113)
    - Part 5: N-S (Box 19, Volume 113)
    - Part 6: T-Y (Box 19, Volume 113)
  - Early Saybrook families. 1610-1776, 1 volume (Box 20, Volume 114)
  - Genealogical notes on the Springfield, Mass. area. 1650-1830, 1 volume (Box 20, Volume 115)
  - Early Springfield families. 1654-1766, 1 volume (Box 20, Volume 116)
  - Early Windsor families. 1624-1792, 1 volume (Box 20, Volume 117)
  - Early families of Westfield, Mass. 1652-1755, 1 volume (Box 20, Volume 118)
  - Connecticut genealogical data. 1737-1902, 5 volumes (Box 20)
    - Part 1 (Box 20, Volume 119)
    - Part 2 (Box 20, Volume 119)
    - Part 3 (Box 21, Volume 119)
    - Part 4 (Box 21, Volume 119)
    - Part 5 (Box 21, Volume 119)
  - Card index. 1800-1900, 1 box (Box 22, Folder 120)
  - Copy of vital records from Mansfield volume "Vital Statistics and ear marks, 1 envelope (Box 21, Folder 121)
    Incomplete.
  - Bliss and Hitchcock family marriage records, 1 volume (Box 21, Volume 122)
  - Chatham, Conn. marriages. 1750-1850, 1 volume (Box 21, Volume 123)
  - Cheshire, Conn. marriages. 1775-1848, 1 volume (Box 21, Volume 124)
  - Bailey's Connecticut marriage records A-B. 1700-1799, 1 volume (Box 22, Volume 125)
  - Abstracts of marriage notices taken from Connecticut newspapers. 1800-1835, 2 volumes (Box 22, Volume 126)
    Part 1: A-Hi; Part 2: Ho-V.
  - Abstracts of marriage records from Connecticut and Massachusetts church records. 1761-1800, 1 volume (Box 22, Volume 127)
  - Marriage notices from Connecticut newspapers, A-E. 1810-1833, 1 volume (Box 22, Volume 128)
  - East Hampton, Conn. marriages. 1733-1850, 1 volume (Box 22, Volume 129)
  - East Hartford, Conn. marriages. 1761-1853, 1 volume (Box 22, Volume 130)
  - East Windsor, Conn. marriages. 1820-1850, 1 volume (Box 23, Volume 131)
  - Glastonbury, Conn. marriages. 1772-1799, 1 volume (Box 23, Volume 132)
  - Abstract of Mansfield, Conn. marriages. 1712-1849, 1 volume (Volume Oversize 133)
  - Abstracts of marriage notices from Hartford newspapers, N-Z. 1800-1830, 1 volume (Box 23, Volume 134)
  - Middletown, Conn. marriages. 1781-1835, 1 volume (Box 23, Volume 135)
  - New Haven marriages from church records. 1702-1891, 1 volume (Box 23, Volume 136)
  - Simsbury, Conn. marriage data. 1663-1777, 1 volume (Box 23, Volume 137)
  - Southington, Burlington, Goshen, New Hartford, Conn. marriages. 1732-1850, 1 volume (Box 23, Volume 138)
  - Suffield, Conn. marriages. 1706-1850, 1 volume (Box 23, Volume 139)
  - Wethersfield, Conn. marriages. 1677-1833, 1 volume (Box 23, Volume 140)
  - Windsor, Conn. marriages. 1671-1690, 1 volume (Box 23, Volume 141)
  - Woodstock, Conn. marriages. 1700-1850, 1 volume (Box 23, Volume 142)
  - Register of pedigree of Lucius Albert Barbour. 1700-1899, 1905; 1 volume (Volume Oversize 143)
  - The Pedigree of Charlotte Cordelia Hilliard, 1652-, 1907; 1 volume (Volume Oversize 144)
  - Pedigree of Lucius Albert Barbour. 1846-1922, 1 volume (Volume Oversize 145)
  - Ancestors of Alice Cordelia Barbour, 1 volume (Volume Oversize 146)
  - Ancestors of John Barber, Jr. and Elizabeth Case, 1 volume (Volume Oversize 147)
  - Ancestors of Rev. John Bulkeley, John Charles Bulkeley, John Drake, William Marion and Julia Niles Ely, 1 volume (Volume Oversize 148)
  - Ancestral charts. 1777-1833, 1 volume (Volume Oversize 149)
  - The pedigree of Elisha Earnest Hilliard. 1600-1916, 1 volume (Volume Oversize 150)
  - Lucius B. Barbour's ancestral lines. 1663-1773, 1 volume (Box 23, Volume 151)
  - Scrapbook of newspaper clippings relating to Connecticut. 1873-1888, 1 volume (Box 23, Volume 152)
    Various death notices of prominent people and events of the day.
  - Scrapbook of clippings from the Norwalk Hour relating to Connecticut genealogy. 1913-1918, 1 volume (Box 23, Volume 153)
    Vital statistics and family genealogies
  - Scrapbook of newspaper clippings, 1 volume (Box 23, Volume 154)
    Partial contents: Woodstock ancient records; Thompson church records; Ellen D. Larned's historical column; N.W. Leavitt's "Early Reminiscences".
  - Deaths from newspapers, A-C. 1810-1833, 1 volume (Box 24, Volume 155)
    Notices of deaths taken from newspapers.
  - Burials at Old North Cemetery, Hartford, Conn. 1831-1908, 1 volume (Box 24, Volume 156)
  - Records from cemeteries in Connecticut. East Hartford, Hockanum, Spencer Street and Buckland cemeteries. 1735-1893 / Collected and arranged by S. Maria Williams, 1 volume (Box 24, Volume 157)
    Arranged alphabetically by town.
  - Cemetery inscriptions copied from Wethersfield, Old Saybrook, Newington, Rocky Hill and Glastonbury cemeteries. 1721-1903, 1 volume (Box 24, Volume 158)
  - Inscriptions from the Ancient Burying Ground in Hartford / copied by C. J. Hoadly, 1877; 1 volume (Box 24, Volume 159)
  - Genealogical notes on Jerijah Barber and inscriptions copied from the Old South Burying Ground, Hartford, Conn., 1877; 1 volume (Box 24, Volume 160)
  - Index of volume 1, Manwaring Digest. 1653-1698, 1 volume (Volume Oversize 161)
    Index of probate records.
  - A continuous family genealogy and record of events, 1613-1900 / by James Carleton Arms, 1895; 1 volume (Box 24, Volume 162)
  - Hartford items from newspapers, church records, etc. 1784-1833, 1 volume (Box 24, Volume 163)
    Abstract of genealogical information.
  - Marriage and death notices from the Christian Secretary published by Philemon Canfield...for the Connecticut Baptist Convention, volumes i-iv. 1824-1827, 1 volume (Box 24, Volume 164)
  - Marriage and death notices from the Christian Secretary published by Philemon Canfield...for the Connecticut Baptist Convention, volumes i-iv. 1824-1827, 1 volume (Box 24, Volume 164)
  - Cemetery inscriptions from Connecticut cemeteries. 1676-1910, 1 volume (Box 24, Volume Oversize 165)
  - Connecticut deaths, 1 volume (Box 24, Volume 166)
  - Bethlehem cemetery inscriptions, 2 volumes (Box 24, Volume 167)
  - Roxbury cemetery inscriptions, 2 volumes (Box 24, Volume 168)
  - Southbury cemetery inscriptions, 1 volume (Box 24, Volume 169)
  - Washington cemetery inscriptions, 3 volumes (Box 24, Volume 170)
  - Inscriptions in the "Town Cemetery"...Washington, Conn. 1775-1838, 1 volume (Box 24, Volume 171)
  - Woodbury cemetery inscriptions, 3 volumes (Box 24, Volume 172)
  - Index to Historical Catalogue of the First Church in Hartford, 1 volume (Box 24, Volume 173)
  - Index to genealogical sketches of the early settlers of West Simsbury now Canton, Conn. by Abiel Brown, 1 volume (Box 25, Volume 174)
  - Harriet Elizabeth Barnes Barbour letters to her parents, 1877-1882; 41 documents (Box 25, Volume 175)
  - Lucius A. Barbour letters to his parents while abroad, 1871-1872; 42 documents (Box 25, Volume 176)
  - Early families of Westerly, R.I. 1612-1763, 1 volume (Box 25, Volume 177)
  - Abstracts of marriage records from Plainfield, Sterling and Voluntown, Conn. and vicinity. 1765-1846, 1 volume (Box 25, Volume 178)
  - Genealogical notes compiled from Connecticut vital records and Matthew Grant Record. 1638-1816, 1 volume (Box 25, Volume 179)
  - Genealogical notes regarding the Barbour and allied families. 1640-1907, 1 volume (Box 25, Volume 180)
  - Early Hartford families, 1 volume + 1 envelope (Volume Oversize 181)
  - Abstract of deaths from cemetery in Sandisfield, Mass. 1768-1867, 1 cardfile box (Box 25, Volume 182)
    Alphabetical listing on cards.